PRIYANK GUPTA

linkedin.com/in/priyank-qupta98 • +1 (682) 716 5526 • priyankgupta2003@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Skilled professional with 4 years of experience at Infosys Ltd in Cloud Computing and Big Data. I focus on developing and deploying data engineering tools using java, python, Scala, Hadoop, spring, and spark.

Now, I am pursuing a master's degree in computer science at the University of Texas at Arlington.

Currently, I am looking for summer internships in 2023

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Arlington

Arlington, TX

Masters in computer science

Fall,22 - Currently Pursuing

• Relevant Coursework: Modelling Techniques, Cloud Computing, Big Data management

Amity University

Uttar Pradesh, India

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

Jul 2014 - May 2018

• Relevant Coursework: Advance Java, Python, Algorithms, Distributed Systems, Probability and Statistics, **Database Systems**

EXPERIENCE

Infosys Ltd. (Client: Citi Bank)

Maharashtra, India

Technology Analyst

Jul.2021- Jul.2022

- Designed & developed a highly available Real-time application using Spark Streaming and Kafka ingestion framework to load the data in Couchbase to act as a central data lake.
- Engineered data pipelines for ingestion, transformation, cleaning, and updates
- Worked collaboratively with Business Analysts, Data Scientists, and other internal partners to identify opportunities/problems.
- Designed data schema and operate internal data warehouses and NoSQL database systems (CouchBase Db).
- Developed core functionality features like updating and persisting of records and parsing Kafka messages.
- Monitor and troubleshoot operational or data issues in the data pipelines.
- Provided assistance to the team with troubleshooting, researching the root cause, and thoroughly resolving defects in the event of a problem.

Infosys Ltd. (Client: Wells Fargo Bank)

Technology Analyst

Maharashtra, India Feb,2019- Jun,2021

- Design, implement, and automate the deployment of our distributed system for collecting and processing log events from multiple sources.
- Spearheaded 20+ team meetings every quarter to elicit cluster bugs and troubleshooting issues.
- Collaborated with developers, to deploy and optimize their applications
- Written scripts to backup Namenode metadata, MySQL DBS, and configurations with a retention period as a part of the disaster recovery process.
- Created various API-based scripts using python/bash scripts- Start Stop all service scripts, Basic Service Validation Script, to check Long running Jobs, DB Back up, Solr Cluster Status script, Cluster Performance Script.
- In record time, identified and fixed production issues, winning the respect and trust of clients.
- Installing, Upgrading, and Administrating Hadoop clusters.

SKILLS

- Databases: Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Apache Hive, CouchBase, MongoDB, Apache Hbase
- Languages: Scala, Python, Java, C/C++, SQL/PL-SQL, Javascript, HTML/XML
- Framework: Spark, Apache Hadoop, Kafka, MapReduce
- Tools: Virtual Studio Code, Eclipse, GitHub, GitLab